elementalled.com 2009-06-19

# LED Lights, Light Strips & Color Changing Lighting – ElementalLED.com Privacy Notice

**ElementalLED.com Privacy Notice**  

By visiting ElementalLED.com.com you agree to accept the practices described in this Privacy Notice.

**Changes to this Privacy Notice, Conditions of Use and Notices:**

This Privacy Notice and our Terms of Use will change over time and the use of information which we gather now is subject to these Notices and Terms as modified. Please check this page periodically as you continue to use our site to see if any changes have been made. This privacy notice was most recently changed on July 24, 2008. If you visit our Web site your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Notice and our Terms of Use, including the application of the laws of the State of California.

**Personal Information Collected By ElementalLED.com:**

ElementalLED.com uses information that we collect from our visitors to personalize and improve your visit at ElementalLED.com and ElementalLED. We gather the following types of information:

Information you give us: ElementalLED.com collects any information which you enter on our Web site. This information is normally provided when you search, buy, participate in a contest, sweepstakes or on-line survey, or when you communicate with any of our departments such as customer service, sales or technical services through our Web site, telephone, mail or fax. You also provide information when you establish an account with us. Examples of the type of information you may supply us with include your name, address, telephone number, credit card information, e-mail addresses, and financial information such as your Social Security number.

**Automatic Information collected by us:** Whenever you visit our Web site we collect and store information such as "cookies" which remember information about a visitor from one page to the next and from one visit to the next. We collect and analyze the IP address used to connect your computer to the Internet; login; password; computer and connection information such as your browser type and version; operating system and platform; purchase history; confirmation when you open e-mail that we send you; the URLs which lead you to and around our Web site including the date and time; the pages and or products you viewed or searched for and the phone number used to call our voice telephone numbers. Your browser allows you to reject cookies and software is available from third parties which will allow you to visit our Web site without providing this information. You are welcomed at our Web site if you use this software but we will not be able to offer you our personalized services.

**Orders:** If you place an order we use a secure order form which requires you to provide contact, billing, and financial information. This information is transmitted to your credit card company to authorize your purchase. At certain times we may offer financing options with or without third party participation. If you use a financing option information provided by you (such as your address, birth date, social security number, and credit card number) may be used to request a credit report from third parties or may be sent to a third party for processing.

**Action Tags:** ElementalLED.com's web pages may contain action tags set by third party firms for the purpose of collecting anonymous information about the usage of our site by customers. Action tags are also known as web beacons or 1 pixel gifs. Action tags are a technique used to compile aggregated statistics about the effectiveness of our web site. They do not use personally identifiable information, such as names or addresses, and do not link online actions to an identifiable person.  
Sharing of Information with third-parties:

**Affiliated Businesses and Elemental LED LLC:** We may share any information that you supply to us with any affiliated business that is substantially controlled by ElementalLED.com and ElementalLED.com Corporation. Any information that is shared this way will be subject to this Privacy Notice.

**Independent Contractors:** We may employ other companies or individuals to provide certain services to us such as sending e-mail, providing click to call telephone calling services, analyzing customer lists and data, providing marketing assistance, or consulting services. These third parties will have access to the information needed to perform their functions but cannot use that information for any other purpose.

**Third party service providers:** Third party service providers have their own privacy and data collection policies which are not controlled by ElementalLED.com. We have no responsibility or liability for these policies and urge you to contact the third party provider if you have any questions. We may occasionally partner with Third parties in various email programs. 

**Orders and Catalog Requests:** When you place your order and/or when you request that we send you product pdf files from time to time we may share your name, mailing address and purchase category information with a few carefully selected marketing partners who may bring you offers of interest. If you wish to opt out of sharing this information with these companies, please call 1 877 564 5051 or e-mail answers@ElementalLED.com.com. We will never share any telephone number(s), or financial information which you have given us with any marketing partner(s).

**Aggregate information:** We provide aggregate information to some of our business partners. This information does not allow them to identify you individually.

**Vendors:** We provide some of our vendors with your contact information so that they may contact you directly with product support information.

**Credit card companies and shippers:** When you buy something from us we send your credit card information, name, billing address and the amount of your purchase to your credit card company to verify and authorize the purchase. Your name, telephone number and shipping information must be provided to third party shippers such as UPS, Federal Express and the United States Postal Service to deliver your purchase.

**Third Party Transaction-Level Data:** If you visit our site from a third-party site the third-party site may be able to access your individual transaction information. In order to track and credit your transaction the third-party site may give you a unique code, cookie or graphic which will uniquely identify you. This will only happen if you link directly from a third party site to our Web site. Any transactions made at our Web site while such a code is active will be reported back to the third party site. We will only report non-personal information to these sites such as the date of the transaction, the product(s) purchased and the amount spent. We will not report any information to these third party sites that will allow them to personally identify you, however based on information which may have previously been collected from you by the third party site they may be able to personally identify you by combining the information they have gathered with the information sent by us. You should read the privacy policy posted by the third party site to see how they may use this information. The presence of a 3rd party navbar atop our site is an indication that the third party site may be able to see your activity on our site.

**Third Party Ads, Surveys and Promotions:** We may use third parties to display ads, surveys and various promotions on our site. These will always be labeled with the third party name. These third party applications may contain cookies or other code which are outside of our control. Although we will attempt to only work with third parties who respect your privacy we are not responsible or liable for any information collected by these third parties or how it is used. You should contact the third party directly or check the third party's privacy Notice to see how any information that they may gather will be used.

**Link to Third Party Site:** Our Web site contains links to third party sites, such as our vendors. ElementalLED.com is not responsible or liable for the privacy practices or content found on these sites. We suggest that you check the Privacy Notice of each site you visit.

**Third Party Checkout Links:** If you use a third party checkout link on our site such as the AOL Quick Checkout Program or Microsoft Passport wallet service your name, billing and shipping addresses and credit card information is transferred to us from your account with the third party to enable you to check out of our site without having to re-enter certain information.

**Law Enforcement and Protection of Users:** We will release personally identifiable information to third parties and organizations when we believe it is appropriate for us to do so to comply with the law. We will also do so to cooperate with law enforcement investigations, comply with court orders or subpoenas, protect the legal rights of us and our users, or when we believe it is needed for fraud protection and/ or credit risk reduction.

**Business Transfer:**

In the unlikely event that ElementalLED.com is sold, has substantially all of its assets acquired or merges or becomes affiliated with any other individual or entity any customer information owned or under the control of ElementalLED.com may be one of the transferred assets.

**Security:**

Our Web site protects the security of personal information you transmit to us by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts the information you input during the transmission to us. We do not reveal your credit card number when we confirm your order. In order to protect against unauthorized access to your account you should sign off when you finish visiting our site.

**Choice/Opt-Out:**

Our Web site gives you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us. If you no longer wish to receive communications from us you may opt-out by calling 877-564-5051 or e-mail answers@elementalled.com

**Children's Online Policy**

ElementalLED.com is committed to the preservation of online privacy for all of its web site visitors, including children. Consistent with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, we will not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. ElementalLED.com.com sells products intended for purchase by adults. If you make a purchase on ElementalLED.com.com, you are representing that you are an adult. If you are a child under the

age of 13, you must ask your parent or guardian to assist you in using ElementalLED.com.com and ElementalLED.com.
